What miraculous good fortune!
Had I not spilled that coffee…
How… Howie that possible? I…
Puny waif…
So you poked your nose around
to find Stray Cat, too!
Why bother…
As long as I keep
Bites the Dust activated,
it will function
to keep protecting you.
I… I blew it!
I-It's almost time!
You tried to off me
with one of Stray Cat's
compressed air projectiles…
Hayato, there's no way you would
have come up with such an idea
if you hadn't already experienced
this morning three, no, four times.
The fact that you have
lived through this morning
four times now…
Tells me that Bites the Dust
is destined
to eradicate not just Rohan,
but at least one of
his mates as well.
Which means you mentioned something
about me to Rohan and someone else.
Or perhaps you were the center
of some kind of interrogation.
Now whom did you murder?
Hm? Did you see a little runt
by the name of Koichi?
What about Jotaro Kujo?
To receive news of his demise
would send me over the moon.
It's all over…
It's far too risky for me
to let you relive this morning
any more than you already have.
It'll only open me up to attack.
Once the others die,
I'll temporarily disengage
Bites the Dust.
Bites the Dust is all powerful!
Luck is finally on
Yoshikage Kira's side!
That name…
The name you said just now…
Oops, did I just disclose
my true name?
You heard it, I'm Yoshikage Kira.
Feel free to tell anyone
you would like.
By the way, what time is it?
I…
I didn't tell a soul.
I never said a single word
to a single person, ever.
I only made a phone call.
He said that he overslept
and was late,
so I found his number
and woke him up.
I called him from the house
this morning, nothing more!
You gave it away.
You gave away your identity, you!
I was just biding my time.
Waiting for him to ditch
the extra winks
and get here a little earlier!
Breakdown, Breakdown
(Listen up)
Let the voice of love
take you higher
Let the gathering forces
overcome time itself
Let the joy of love
give you an answer
Our Willis unbreakable
even when it's time to part
1999 Bizarre Summer
This is the hymn born from
our fearless hearts
Great Days
Breakdown, Breakdown
JOJO'S BIZARRE ADVENTURE
DIAMOND IS UNBREAKABLE
EPISODE 37
SHINING D (DIAMOND)
IS UNBREAKABLE, PART 1
Hey, Josuke.
We're gonna make it to
the big meeting on time after all.
Stop right there, Okuyasu!
I can't say
if it's pure chance or fate,
but I just heard this guy
say a certain name,
and I don't believe my ears.
I don't believe it!
I know what I heard,
you just uttered the name
"Yoshikage Kira".
Huh? What?!
What are the chances…
This is no chance!
This isn't fate at work either!
It's called making a gamble!
I made a huge bet!
And he just arrived!
There's no doubt you said it!
That name just
came out of your mouth!
It can't be…
Dirty killer!
Don't worry, if you happen
to have the same exact name,
I can heal you
at any time I need to.
This bastard's Yoshikage Kira?
Th-That's impossible… You brat!
This can't be happening…
I have to turn off Bites the Dust
so I can protect myself!
Get back here, Deadly Queen!
I'm getting cold…
The rain is trickling
down my back now.
Dammit,
can no one show up on time?
Oh?
That's Koichi and Jotaro.
Yes! I beat the clock!
I beat destiny!
I was never one
for rapturous highs.
No, my goal is a life
sans dispiriting lows…
to live as carefree as a daisy,
to live with peace
and tranquility.
You've finally revealed
your true self!
Now let me knock that peace and
tranquility right off your face.
Who would've guessed
we'd happen to run into
the guy from Rohan's picture.
I don't think we just ran into
this guy by chance, Okuyasu.
I don't know exactly
what's going on here,
but the fact that he just revealed
his real name to Hayato Kawajiri,
tells me we got here
in just the nick of time.
I should tell you, I wasn't
running away from you fools.
I can obliterate any one of you
the instant the thought
occurs to me.
I simply detest conflict.
Conflict runs completely counter to
the peace and tranquility
I strive for, and I despise it.
It's really quite simple to
rise victorious in a single battle,
but then the stress begins to
pile up before the next one.
It's a foolish endeavor.
To engage in conflict
is to engage in endless futility.
It's because you murdered Shigechi
that we're here now, freak in idiot!
Some sick sonuvabitch whose
hobby is killing innocent people
shouldn't get the privilege
of flapping his gums,
you cat-eyed piece of shit!
Be careful, Josuke!
Don't touch that creepy ass
Deadly Queen's hand.
You just heard the reason
for my not obliterating all of you.
The only souls standing between
me and my peace and tranquility
is you three.
I have no choice
but to battle those
who dare discover my true identity.
Hey, Hayato Kawajiri,
go get behind us now.
Shining Diamond's range
is 1 -2 meters,
it has the ability to correct
that which has been
destroyed or altered.
I won't be needing to fix
anything on you, buddy!
Just a good ol' fashioned
ass kicking for you!
Josuke!
Dora.
He's tough…
Yes! I can't see them,
but hell yeah!
Kira just hacked up blood
and went flying through the air!
You're freak in slow as molasses,
Deadly Queen!
I guess being hell-bent
on peace and tranquility
made you a little lethargic.
Your Stand just isn't cut out
for one-on-one fighting.
Josuke, he's slow,
but don't let down your guard!
If you wanna knock him around
without laying a finger on him,
there's nothing better than
The Hand.
Bring it!
Grabbing sections of the void
to transport, eh?
My aim was for Josuke, but I seem
to have been turned around…
I am now poised to attack you.
It was inside my bag…
What?!
All's well that ends well.
Not bad for beginner's luck.
Nothing was touching me,
nothing at all…
It was the air… the air spit fire!
Okuyasu!
Th-The air… spit fire?
The air…
Now you can see why
I held onto this little darling.
I can use Stray Cat's
air-controlling abilities
in Deadly Queen's explosions.
Hayato, thank you for
carting it all the way here!
The invisibility of air,
the indefensibility
of an explosion!
Could there be a more powerful
combination of elements?
I can't believe he was
nurturing it to do this…
And I'm the one
who brought it here!
I did say luck was finally
on my side, didn't I?
Then again, the two characters
that make up the word luck
are bring and life…
How utterly appropriate.
THE HAND
Is something wrong, Mr. Jotaro?
No, it's nothing.
It's just the rain,
I thought I heard Josuke.
I'm sure the slob overslept again.
If he's not here in five minutes,
I'm going straight to
Hayato Kawajiri's school,
you can wait with everyone else.
You're gonna be
as good as new, Okuyasu!
That's certainly a noble thought.
But first I'm going to
blow you sky high.
It launched air at you
like a bullet!
It's transforming air
into an explosive!
It's coming! You've got to run now!
You can't see it?
It's that weird bubble like thing!
I-It's gonna get you!
Good as new?
He's gonna use his powers
to heal Okuyasu…
The power to correct
that which is broken…
Impressive you were
able to reassemble
broken stone into a wall
within seconds.
I-It's at it again!
I-It's coming!
Nothing evokes more terror
than the act of assumption.
Especially for those who assume
the false superiority of
their own talents and abilities.
I-It's squeezing through!
Contact didn't cause it to explode!
Hmph. I thought the explosion
would decapitate him,
but lucky for him the destructive
force was rather shallow.
Deadly Queen's explosion is not
limited to the objects it touches.
Thinking so would be
an assumption.
It can generate an explosion
at any distance I wish.
No matter where you try to hide,
no matter how quickly you build
a protective stone wall
or metal plate,
my bomb will slip through any
obstacle and execute its target!
Your days of escaping
with your life are over.
Die!
It's no use!
There's no way to dodge it!
Escaping?
I have no intention of escaping…
Never had,
in case you'd like to know.
How else would I heal up Okuyasu!
He's charging right into it?!
He went through it!
I thought you could detonate
that thing at any distance?
I guess there's an exception.
If you were to blow me up
at a range too close to you, Kira,
the result couldn't be very good,
could it?!
All right, Okuyasu.
Now I can fix you.
You can't touch him!
No, he didn't… I think he might've
turned Okuyasu's body into a…
Dammit that brat Hayato…
How could he… no…
I didn't see Deadly Queen
touch Okuyasu.
How do you know this,
Hayato Kawajiri?!
You're not a Stand user!
I'm totally sure!
I've lived in the same house
as him until this morning!
His face tells me everything!
It touched him
before we could notice!
I know that's what happened!
Okuyasu has been
turned into a bomb!
Yoshikage Kira!
There's no telling for sure…
I mean you did storm at me
out of the blue,
I'm really not sure whether
I did in fact touch Okuyasu.
It was all such a blur.
Perhaps I should simply
press the switch and find out?
D-Don't, Yoshikage Kira!
Just hurry up and
shoot your next air missile!
Point that damn thing at me
and shoot, come on!
Now there's no need to be hasty
and shoot you now is there…
Josuke Higashikata, it does me
no harm to observe your movements
and then decide
whether I obliterate you.
Who's to say Okuyasu
isn't a bomb at all.
Maybe you could heal him
with Shining Diamond.
I might be overstepping my bounds,
but at this point you have only one
avenue to saving Okuyasu…
And that is to heal him
through the mode of touch.
Even if he is a human bomb now,
touching him with Shining Diamond
may kill you, but Okuyasu
won't explode into oblivion.
Sacrifice yourself,
and you'll at least heal your dear
friend's critical injuries, yes?
You can't touch him!
I'll wait until
you make your decision.
Do you make physical contact with
your best friend and save his life
or do you charge me?
The choice is yours.
I'll wait as long as it takes,
but it seems
you're averse to touching,
even when it means saving
your number one friend…
I have proof touching him
is deadly!
I know for sure he can control
only one bomb at a time!
Once he's activated one bomb,
he can't use the next one
until the first has exploded.
Otherwise, why wouldn't he launch
a bunch of bombs…
He's using only one at a time!
He's made Okuyasu into a bomb,
so he can't shoot now!
Just what are you getting at?
I'm saying there's a way
to save Okuyasu!
And that's…
Deadly Queen, bomb switch on.
I just need to touch him!
What?!
H-Hayato, you…
I get it now! Shining Diamond!
You're one crazy sonuvabitch,
Hayato Kawajiri…
That took some major balls.
And you're in grade school?
The only way I was able to do it
was because I knew
you could heal me.
Besides, I couldn't just
watch you die.
If you're gone, he'll off me
in the blink of an eye,
and he'll be free
to do whatever he wants.
It's just a matter of time
before he kills my mom…
and more innocent people
right here in this town!
Sorry, but you will die.
To think your power to heal
can reverse my destructive acts
in the fraction of a second…
I had forgotten how utterly
annoying your pathetic power is.
Deadly Queen!
Josuke, he's gonna shoot!
It will detonate on impact
so that you will have
no opportunity to guard.
But because you could
sidestep a contact explosive
if you happen to see it,
I've launched one so small
it's almost impossible to detect.
With Okuyasu on your back,
and those painful shrapnel wounds,
can you really dodge
an explosive projectile…
Just get the hell out of there,
Josuke!
If the explosion so much
as brushes you, you'll be a goner!
Okuyasu! I fixed you all up.
Open your eyes, Okuyasu!
Get out of there! He'll get you!
Eight meters until impact.
It's time to wake up now, buddy!
You're good as new, Okuyasu!
Josuke!
Seven meters to go.
Open your god damned eyes,
Okuyasu! Hey!
Hey, Okuyasu! Quit napping and
open your freak in eyes!
Hey! Let's knock the shit
out of this asshole,
just like the good ol' days!
Josuke…
Like Joe Montana
throwing a touch down pass,
I'll plant my bomb
firmly under your nose,
and detonate the sucker
in the perfect position.
Four meters until impact.
Drop him! You've gotta run,
or it'll hit you dead on!
Okuyasu is… Okuyasu is already…
Shut the hell up!
You're the only one
who needs to run, kid!
Two meters till show time.
The explosion has about
a three-meter radius.
I see it! It's about two meters
in front of you!
You gotta run now!
Okuyasu… Okuyasu is already dead!
He's nowhere near dead, dammit!
Okuyasu is in great shape!
He's going to open his eyes!
One more meter and
the switch goes click.
Josuke!
SPLASH
Th-The air bullet was
ruptured by a blade of blood!
Did Josuke somehow take his blood
and propel it with so much force
that it cut like a knife?
That's it!
Just like that time in the attic…
When I punctured them
with the compass needle,
the cat plant's
air shackles deflated!
He used the blood from his gashes
like a water jet cutter…
to sever it clean through…
But what about
that pressurized air bullet…
It didn't deflate!
It's getting closer!
An air bullet turned
improvised explosive device
is stabilized by Deadly Queen.
That's why it does not deflate!
You can smash it
or dice it into tiny pieces,
but the bomb
will not lose its power!
Of course,
it will detonate on impact.
Yes, finally touch down.
Huh? H-His body…
is floating?
Explode!
No, this isn't floating…
Shining Diamond
won't let me heal myself,
but if it's pieces of road
like the ones that got lodged
in me from that first blast…
that's a whole different story!
The pieces of road stuck in
his body actually pulled him up!
I'm out of options.
This isn't our house,
but it's our refuge for now,
Hayato.
I'm asking you to please leave
Okuyasu behind.
If you continue to carry Okuyasu,
you'll be killed!
He'll corner you
and kill you for sure!
I asked you to keep quiet,
okay, Hayato?
Okuyasu and I have a connection.
He's my friend!
No that's not what I mean!
By the time you healed Okuyasu,
he was already dea—
I said enough!
Enough. Don't say another word.
You've got to focus on beating him!
It makes me sick…
That blasted ability to correct…
without it,
my bomb would be unstoppable.
The greatest obstacle to
my attaining peace and tranquility
isn't Jotaro.
It's him!
Josuke Higashikata!
EPISODE 38
SHINING D (DIAMOND)
IS UNBREAKABLE, PART 2